The intense battle has reached its endgame and Meng Ao has finally faced off against Lian Po.
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）
激烈なる戦いは 最終局面を迎え
蒙驁(もうごう)は ついに廉頗(れんぱ)と相対した
Will this man who has suffered numerous defeats finally have vindication with this one-on-one fight?!
敗北を重ねた男への雪辱を―
この一騎打ちで
果たすことができるのか？
In that era, the State of Qin Six Great Generals and us State of Zhao Three Great Devas
（廉頗）あの時代 秦国(しんこく)六大将軍と
わしら趙国三大天(ちょうこく さんだいてん)は―
互いに数百万の兵の血肉を握りしめ
grasped the flesh and blood of millions of soldiers
and did nothing but devote ourselves completely to clashing them with each other!
全身全霊を懸けて
それをぶつけ合う戦いに明け暮れた
（信(しん)）アッ… アア…
Even if some heat has been lost with such opponents gone,
（廉頗）その相手を失い
熱きものがなくなったとはいえ
あの黄金の時代を
戦い抜いた この金剛の体
this adamantine body made from fighting through that golden age still remains!
うぬの
しみったれた40年の思いとやらで
And you thought your mangy 40 years of feelings or whatever
吹き飛ばされるとでも思ったのか！
could blow that all away?!
あまり わしらをナメるなよ 蒙驁！
Do not make such light of me, Meng Ao!
Unfading Era
こ… これが廉頗
Th-This is... Lian Po!
The Great General said to have fought on-par with Wang Qi and those other generals.
あの王騎(おうき)将軍たちと 互角の勝負を
繰り広げてきたっていう大将軍
確かに 王騎将軍と同じように―
Yeah, just like General Wang Qi, I can definitely feel an insane "pressure" just from him standing there.
ただ そこにいるだけで
すげえ威圧を感じる
But unlike General Wang Qi, with Lian Po standing there as an enemy...
ただ 王騎将軍と違って
廉頗は 敵として立っている分
さっきから
心臓を握られたみてえに息苦しい…
my heart's been hurting like it's being squeezed.
That's some damn heavy pressure.
ものすげえ重圧感だ
（蒙驁）フォ…
火の消えたことを認めるのか
You've acknowledged that the light has gone out?
And yet you've still entered the battlefield?
おぬしともあろう者が
それでも戦場に出てくるとは
Of course. You are not my goal.
当然 うぬが目当てではないわ
ねらいは 王翦(おうせん)と桓騎(かんき)じゃった
My goal was Wang Jian and Huan Ji.
And while I did actually oppose Wang Jian,
まあ 王翦とは実際 対峙(たいじ)してみたが
わしの心に響くものは
少なかったのぅ
he resonated with me very little.
フォフォ… ウソをつけ
（廉頗）うん？
Don't lie.
王翦 桓騎は
間違いなく六大将軍級の武将じゃ
Wang Jian and Huan Ji are both undoubtedly military commanders of the same class as the Six Great Generals.
The fact that you could not feel that
じゃが
おぬしが感じ入らなかったのは―
本気で それを
求めてきたのではないからじゃ
means that that was not seriously what you were seeking.
廉頗 おぬしが出てきた理由
それは １年前の―
Lian Po. The reason you reemerged...
is because of your resentment that one year ago...
王騎が討ち取られたことへの
憤りであろうが？
Wang Qi was killed.
王騎将軍が討ち取られたから？
It's because General Wang Qi... was killed?
When Wang Qi was defeated by the practically unknown Li Mu and Pang Nuan...
ほぼ無名の
李牧(りぼく)と龐煖(ほうけん)に敗れた王騎は―
結果的に
時代の流れに のまれる形となった
it was like he had been swallowed by the passage of eras.
いや…
No, with the exception of you, it was because all of the Six Great Generals and Three Great Devas had now been...
そもそも 六大将軍も三大天も
おぬしを除いて皆が
それが許せぬのであろう？ 廉頗
And you could not forgive that, could you, Lian Po?
With no way to fight against this...
あらがいようのない この…
（廉頗）
時代の流れが何だというのだ！
What the hell is the passage of eras?!
The strong are the strong to the end!
強者は 最後まで強者
老いようが 病に伏せようが
戦場に出たならば 勝つのが鉄則！
Whether they age or become ill, if they enter the battlefield, the fact that they'll win is ironclad!
だが 王騎は敗れ 死んだ
But Wang Qi lost and died.
長く戦場から離れていたとはいえ
Even if he had been away from the battlefield for a long time,
あれだけ
わしらと激戦を重ね続けた男が―
that man that had fought so many fierce battles with me...
lost in merely one war after his return.
復帰後 僅か１戦でな
（廉頗）あやつは
六大将軍と三大天の名を汚(けが)した…
He was a fool that sullied the name of the Six Great Generals and the Three Great Devas.
愚か者よ
ふざけたこと言ってんじゃねえ！
Quit spouting that bullshit!
うん？
（蒙恬(もうてん)）ハッ…
フン… 童(わっぱ)が　十年早いぞ
Youngster, you're 10 years too early.
わしに もの申したいならば
名乗れる名を手にしてからにしろ
It you want to talk to me, first make a name for yourself.
I have got a name!
名乗る名は持ってる！
飛信(ひしん)隊の信！
Xin of the Feixin Unit!
Isn't that...?!
That's...
これは…
あんたの四天王 輪虎(りんこ)を
この手で討ち取った飛信隊の―
I'm the man that slew Lun Hu,
one of your Four Heavenly Kings.
Xin of the Feixin Unit!
信だ！
General Lun Hu was slain?!
（魏兵）輪虎将軍が討たれた？
（魏兵）バカな！ ありえぬ！
Nonsense, that can't be!
いや しかし…
But...
That is unmistakably Lord Lun Hu's sword!
あれは まさしく輪虎さまの刀
Xin of the Feixin Unit took down Lun Hu?!
（兵士）飛信隊の信が輪虎を？
Then we won the central army battle!
（兵士）
では 中央軍の戦いは こちらが？
（廉頗）いいかげん刀を替えぬか
Would you change swords already?
I'm fine. If I just sharpen them they'll be good as new.
（輪虎）
いいんですよ　研げば戻ります
These are the treasured swords you gave to me, my lord...
殿にいただいた宝刀ですから
死ぬまで僕は これで戦いますよ
So I'm going to fight with these until I die.
You slew Lun Hu?!
輪虎を討ったじゃとー！
（楽華(がくか)隊兵）た… 隊長！
（騒ぎ声）
C-Captain?!
What're you doing, Xin?!
何してる 信！ 早く逃げろ！
Run, now!
さすがに この体で挑むのは無謀か
I guess it would be pretty reckless to challenge him with my body like this...
クッ… クウッ…
信！
Xin!
But like hell I'm backing down!
だからって ひけるかよ！
I still want to fight.
それに やってみてえ
やって感じてみてえ！
I want to know what it feels like!
六大将軍と互角だったっつう
元三大天 廉頗の力を！
The power of the man said to be on-par with the Six Great Generals, Former Great Deva Lian Po!
信！ 何を！
Xin, what?!
バカなのは分かってる
I know it's stupid.
でも さっきから そうしろって
背中を押されてる気もするんだ
But for a while now, I've had a feeling pushing at my back telling me to do it.
王騎将軍と輪虎の手に！
The hands of General Wang Qi and Lun Hu!
（廉頗）ヌオーッ！
童がー！
Damn youngster!
ウワッ！
What?!
なに！
や… やっぱり ものすげえな
J-Just what I expected. That was freakin' incredible.
大将軍の本気の一撃は…
A serious attack from a Great General...
わしの一撃を止めたじゃと…
He stopped my attack?
何じゃ？ この剣は
What is this sword?
What is this youngster?
何じゃ？
この童…
ウワッ！
（信）アッ…
（兵士）お… おい
H-Hey!
ハァ！
（兵士たち）ウワッ！
（信）グッ…
何をしている 衛兵！ その者を守れ
What are you guards doing?!
Protect that man!
いいかげんにせぬか！
Is that not enough?!
廉頗 もう分かったであろうが？
Lian Po, don't you get it yet?
After the loss of your first Heavenly King, Xuan Feng, you have now lost Lun Hu as well.
おぬしの四天王は
玄峰(げんぽう)に続き 輪虎も討たれた
そして その若者は
おぬしの一撃をも受け止める
And that young man stopped your attack.
時代は
確実に 次の舞台へと向かっておる
The era is without a doubt moving on to the next stage.
But that absolutely...
じゃが
それは決して…
決して あの時代を
色あせさせるものではない！
absolutely will not make the colors of that age fade!
So Lian Po, you are no longer...
（蒙驁）
じゃから 廉頗　おぬしは もう…
（王騎）
コココッ… 納得がいきませんか？
Not convinced?
（王騎）ンフフフッ…
あなたには かないませんね
I guess you can't bear it.
あれだけ やり尽くしたのに
まだ火をともそうとしておられる
You fought so hard and for so long, but you're still trying to keep your flame lit.
（廉頗）フン…
（王騎）ンフフフッ… しかし
もう いいではありませんか 将軍
But do you not think that that is enough, general?
あの時代は もう
あれで完成しているのですから
Because with that, the age is complete.
Lian Po
Hurry!
（魏兵）急げ！
将軍は 既に上で戦っておられるぞ
The general is already fighting up there!
（兵士）走れ！ 持ち場は いい
蒙驁さまをお助けせよ！
Run! Don't worry about your positions!
Save Lord Meng Ao!
If we take a long time here, the difference in forces will only increase!
（側近）このままモタついていたら
戦力差は広がる一方だ
Do you understand that, General Lian Po?!
そのことを
分かっておられるのですか？
廉頗将軍…
Like I give a shit...
（廉頗）時代の流れなど…
about the passing of eras!
知ったことか
信！
Xin!
（蒙恬隊兵）隊長 お下がりを！
（信）お前たち…
Captain, get back!
You guys...
もはや これは一騎打ちではない！
This is no longer a one-on-one fight!
Let's go! Take Meng Ao's head!
行くぞ！ 蒙驁の首を取れ！
（魏兵たち）オーッ！
（馬令）
あっ… 来るぞ！ 将軍を守れ！
Here they come! Protect the general!
乱戦に？ 好都合だ
今は 秦国の兵の数が圧倒的に多い
It's turning into a melee?
This is good for us. Right now the State of Qin's numbers are overwhelmingly greater!
ヌオーッ！
（蒙恬隊兵たち）ウワーッ！
廉頗…
Lian Po...
やべえ… 体が…
This is bad... my body won't move...
Xin!
信！
待て 廉頗！ その者は―
Wait, Lian Po!
That boy was present at Wang Qi's end
王騎の最期に居合わせ
その矛を受け取った者じゃぞ！
and received his lance!
What?
なに？
This kid got Wang Qi's lance?
王騎が矛を この小僧に？
フッ… どうりで
It's no wonder.
There is something I've been interested in for quite some time.
ずっと気になっていたことがある
Kid, answer me honestly.
小僧 正直に答えよ
What was Wang Qi like when he died?
王騎の死に際は どうであった？
敗戦の将となったが 武名を
汚すほどのものではなかったのか…
As a defeated general,
was it not bad enough to defile his military reputation?
それとも 無念のうちに
顔をゆがめて 死んでいったのか…
Or perhaps he died with his face distorted in regret?
どっちでもねえ
It wasn't either.
将軍は“強者が次の強者に討たれ
時代が続いていく”
The general said "The strong are slain by the stronger and the era continues.
“だから 乱世は面白い”って
笑って逝(い)ったんだ
That is why tumultuous ages are interesting," and laughed.
That form was the form of the greatest general under the heavens, admired by all!
その姿は！
誰もが憧れる天下の大将軍の姿！
堂々たる英雄の姿そのものだった！
It was the form of a dignified hero!
Those words don't sound false.
その言葉に偽りは なかろうな？
そうか
I see. Just what I've come to expect from you, Wang Qi...
さすがじゃな 王騎
While saying things like "the era is complete" out loud,
口では
時代は完成したなどと言いながら
you still had a flame smoldering inside you.
貴様自身の中でも まだ
くすぶっている残り火があった
じゃが 半端な思いで
貴様が戦場に戻るはずはない
But I'm sure you did not come back to the battlefield half-heartedly.
Undoubtedly, it was because you discovered a "new fight".
間違いなく
新しい戦いを見いだしたからのはず
Though you lost your footing on the first step of that important journey.
その大事な道を
１歩目で踏み外したというのに…
I see. But still, you came to terms with the world and laughed on your way out.
そうか　それでも 貴様は―
全てと折り合いをつけて
笑って逝けたんじゃな
フッ… まったく
Geez...
Every one of these guys, selfishly going before me...
どいつも こいつも
自分勝手に 先に逝きおって…
（蒙驁）廉頗
Lian Po, now that the Six Great Generals are gone, you no longer have any opponents.
六大将軍亡き今
おぬしの相手は もはや おらぬ
Fighting without an opponent can only feel empty.
相手がおらぬのに戦おうとしても
むなしいだけじゃて
じゃが おぬしにとって この戦いに
意義を見つけるとするなら―
But if you try to find some meaning in this fight,
それは 大将軍 廉頗の
矛を置く最終戦とすることじゃ
it can be the final battle of the Great General Lian Po where he lays down his lance.
フォフォ… 自分で置けぬなら―
But if you won't lay it down yourself,
わしが その腕ごと
たたき落としてやってもよいぞ
I don't mind chopping off your entire arm.
And if you're so inclined, I'll send you to Wang Qi.
なんなら
王騎の所まで送ってやろうか？
古い よしみじゃ
For old time's sake, let's duke it out to the end.
とことん
最後まで つきあってやるぞい
Grandpa...
じいちゃん…
General Meng Ao.
蒙驁将軍…
（兵士）
うん？ 何だ？ この音は… あっ！
What's that sound?!
（介子坊(かいしぼう)）何を
モタついておられるのですか 殿！
Why are you talking so long, my lord?!
Enemy reinforcements?!
敵の新手か！
（兵士）そ… 側面から来ただと！
Th-They came from the side?!
That can't be! Those are dangerous sheer cliffs!
バカな！ あっちは険しい断崖だぞ
（魏兵）か… 介子坊将軍！
（魏兵）介子坊将軍が来てくれたぞ
G-General Jie Zifang!
General Jie Zifang is here!
介子坊？
General Jie Zifang?!
Their numbers aren't that big!
大した数ではない！
先頭の大男が将だぞ　討ち取れ！
And the big one leading them is a major general!
Take him down!
（介子坊）やかましい！
Silence!
幕だ 秦国軍よ！
This is the final curtain, State of Qin Army!
ンンッ… 何だ？ あの野郎
Who is that bastard?
四天王筆頭 介子坊
よりによって こんなときに…
The head of the Four Heavenly Kings, Jie Zifang!
He shows up now, of all times?!
Everyone, look!
（兵士）みんな あれを見ろ！
（蒙恬）あれは…
What...?
What is it this time?
（兵士）煙？ 敵の本陣から
火が上がっているのか？
Smoke?
There's a fire at the enemy headquarters?!
（兵士）この雨の中？
In this rain?
That's... no ordinary fire.
あれは ただの火じゃない…
That's a signal fire.
（王賁(おうほん)）あれは のろしだ
（王賁）ハッ！ まさか…
Could it be?
魏国軍の本陣を落とした？
The State of Wei headquarters has fallen?!
（兵士）
のろし代わりの火が消えちまう！
The substitute signal fires are going out!
Burn more! Throw oil on them!
（兵士）
もっと燃やせ！ 油も ぶっかけろ！
（白亀西(はくきさい)）クッ… クウッ…
（中貴(ちゅうき)）お頭！
（桓騎）うん？
Boss!
（中貴）下の魏国の連中は
みんな 投降しやした
All of the State of Wei guys down there have surrendered.
Looks like Lei Tu did a really good job.
雷土(らいど)さんが
うまくやったみたいッス
（桓騎）おう よくやった　よ～し
Oh, well done.
Good.
Then next up is your turn, Great General Bai Guixi.
んじゃ
次は あんたの番だな 白亀西大将軍
き… 貴様
Y-You bastard...
どうして…
How?
介子坊の軍に追われ 山中に
逃げ込んでいたのではないのか？
Weren't you taking refuge in the mountains after being chased away by Jie Zifang's army?
Taking refuge? Us?
（桓騎）
逃げ込んでた？ 俺たちが？
(Huan Ji Main Army Scattering)
State of Qin
Headquarters
Jie Zifang
(Xuan Feng
Killed)
Huan Ji
State of Wei
Headquarters
介子坊のヤツを
山ん中で―
We dragged Jie Zifang around to the middle of the mountains.
引きずり回して
やったんだよ
And while he was searching for my main unit,
ヤツが
本隊を捜している間
俺は 別動隊の
４０００の兵を率いて
I led a separate unit of 4,000 on my own accord.
独自に
動いてたってわけだ
So no matter how much they looked, they were never going to find me.
いくら あいつが捜したって
俺のことが見つかる道理はねえ
さて どうするか… いつもは
あっさり スパッとやるんだが
So, what to do now?
Normally I do things completely without hesitation,
あんたにゃ
少々 同情する部分がある
but I've got some sympathy for you.
After all, you're the Supreme Commander in name only. Lian Po was really in control of everything, right?
どうせ 総大将とは名ばかりで
廉頗が全部 仕切ってたんだろう？
何もさせてもらってねえのに
責任取らされちゃ割に合わねえよな
It seems like such a rip off to have to take responsibility when you didn't do anything.
命ごいしろ
Beg for your life.
If you get down on your hands and knees and desperately beg for forgiveness,
（桓騎）地べたに這(は)いつくばって
必死に許しを請えば―
I'll at least spare your life.
命だけは助けてやる
バカにするなよ 若造が！
Do not make a fool of me, youngster!
I am Bai Guixi!
我は白亀西！
魏国軍12万の総大将なり！
Supreme Commander of the State of Wei Army of 120,000!
I'd rather die 100 times over than bow my head to the State of Qin!
秦国に頭を下げるくらいなら
100回でも死んでやるわ！
I'll show you the pride of the people of the State of Wei!
魏国人の誇り 見せてやる！
さっさと殺せ！
Hurry up and kill me!
さあ 殺せ！
C'mon, kill me!
What's wrong, Huan Ji?!
どうした？ 桓騎
ウハハハッ！ おじけづいたか？
Getting cold feet?!
フッ… 何だ？ このおっさん
Man, what's with this old dude?
チッ… なんかシラけたな
I kinda don't feel like this anymore.
Hey, Zhong Gui, take him away.
おい 中貴 連れてけ
Yeah, right.
…なんつってな
グギャー！
（魏兵）白亀西さまー！
Lord Bai Guixi!
おっと… ハハハハッ…
せっかくカッコついたんだ
もうちょい頑張れよ
And you'd finally started to sound cool, too.
Just hang in there a little longer.
（悲鳴）
おい 白亀西
Hey, Bai Guixi.
Between the two armies, 10,000 humans have died in this war.
この戦で 両軍合わせりゃ
万の人間が死んでるぜ
お前が大将っていうんなら―
So if you're the general,
you've gotta share the pain a bit.
少しは 痛みを分かち合わねえとな
俺の手下も あっちで待ってるぜ
A lot of my subordinates are waiting for you on the other side!
（白亀西）ギャ～ッ…
大バカだな　命ごいすりゃ
マジで助けてやったのに
What an idiot. I really would have spared him if he'd just have begged for his life.
（中貴）武人の誇りってやつッスよ
（黒桜(こくおう)）くだらん
That's the pride of a soldier for ya.
Ridiculous.
（桓騎）フン…
Zhong Gui, cut off their heads.
中貴 そいつらの首をはねろ
（中貴）へい
Aye.
Okay, then we're about done here.
さて こっちは大体 片づいた
Now all that's left is to see what's going on over there.
あとは あっちが どうなるかだ
The State of Wei headquarters fell?!
（信）魏国の本陣が落ちたのか？
桓騎か…
Huan Ji?!
や… やったぜ！ 俺たちの勝ちだ！
W-We did it! We won!
No.
いや…
確かに この瞬間は そうだが
Well, that's definitely true for the moment,
but what is the enemy going to do with their general slain?!
大将を討たれた この敵は
ここから…
（介子坊）者ども やれ！
さっさと蒙驁を討ち取って―
Men, get them!
Let's take down Meng Ao and even the state of the war!
戦局を五分に持ち込むぞ！
（魏兵たち）オーッ！
I'm borrowing this horse!
馬を借りるぞ！
蒙驁将軍を安全な所まで！
ここの難さえ しのげば―
Get General Meng Ao to a safe place!
If we can just make it through this...
it really will be our victory!
本当に 我らの勝ちだ！
I will not allow it!
させぬわ！
俺も馬を…
I need a horse, too...
（馬令）殿 お急ぎを！
（兵士）くそ！ 来るぞ！
My lord, we must hurry!
Shit, here they come!
（兵士）ダメだ！
（兵士）介子坊を止められない！
It's no good! We can't stop Jie Zifang!
何じゃ 小娘ーっ！
Who are you, you little girl?!
（蒙恬）よくて相討ちか…
If I'm lucky, we'll strike each other.
But there's still one more enemy we can't handle.
だが
本当に手に負えない敵が もう１人
Let's go, too!
（兵士）こっちも いくぞ！
（兵士）取り囲んで 廉頗を討て！
Surround him and strike down Lian Po!
廉頗…
（介子坊）どけ！
Lian Po.
Out of the way!
蒙驁の首は俺が いただく！
I will take Meng Ao's head!
恬！
Tian!
ウワッ！
Xin!
信！
介子坊！
Jie Zifang!
やめじゃ　帰るぞ！
Stop! We're going home!
We've lost.
わしらの負けじゃ
Preview
Victory... And...
End